{"data": [{"type": "rule", "id": "rule_1", "question": "A person whose driver's license is under suspension may:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "239", "correct": "true", "text": "Not operate a motor vehicle under any circumstances"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "239", "correct": "false", "text": "Operate a motor vehicle in a case of an emergency"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "239", "correct": "false", "text": "Operate a motor vehicle to and from work"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "239", "correct": "false", "text": "Operate a motor vehicle when accompanied by a full G licensed driver"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_2", "question": "What is the maximum blood alcohol concentration (BAC) for fully licensed drivers?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "247", "correct": "false", "text": "0.03%"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "247", "correct": "true", "text": "0.05%"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "247", "correct": "false", "text": "0.08%"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "247", "correct": "false", "text": "1.00%"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_3", "question": "What penalties can a driver face when convicted of driving while their licence is suspended for a Criminal Code Offence:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "261", "correct": "false", "text": "A fine of $5,000-$25,000 and an additional 1 year suspension for a first offence"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "261", "correct": "false", "text": "A fine of $10,000-$50,000 and an additional 2 years of suspension for a subsequent offence within 5 years"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "261", "correct": "false", "text": "Up to 2 years in prison and a three year licence suspension under the Criminal Code"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "261", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_4", "question": "Under what circumstances may a driver's licence be cancelled?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "262", "correct": "false", "text": "If you fail a driver's re-examination"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "262", "correct": "false", "text": "For possession of an altered driver's licence"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "262", "correct": "false", "text": "If you don’t pay your reinstatement fee or administrative monetary penalty following a suspension"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "262", "correct": "true", "text": "Any or all of above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_5", "question": "If you are convicted of careless driving or driving 50 km/h or more over the speed limit, the consequences for a first offence is:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "265", "correct": "false", "text": "Licence suspension for up to 15 days"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "265", "correct": "true", "text": "Licence suspension for up to 30 days"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "265", "correct": "false", "text": "Licence suspension for up to 45 days"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "265", "correct": "false", "text": "Licence suspension for up to 60 days"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_6", "question": "When your suspension period ends, after accumulating 15 demerit points, how many points are you reduced down to?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "267", "correct": "false", "text": "Reduced to 10 points"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "267", "correct": "true", "text": "Reduced to 7 points"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "267", "correct": "false", "text": "Reduced to 5 points"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "267", "correct": "false", "text": "Reduced to 3 points"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_7", "question": "The Ministry of Transportation may suspend a licence after a 9 demerit point interview:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "269", "correct": "false", "text": "If the driver does not have full G licence"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "269", "correct": "true", "text": "If the driver fails to give a satisfactory reasons as to why their licence should not be suspended"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "269", "correct": "false", "text": "A driver's licence may not be suspended before the 10 demerit point mark"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "269", "correct": "false", "text": "A driver's licence may not be suspended before the 15 demerit point mark"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_8", "question": "A class G1 drivers must be accompanied by a class G driver with a blood alcohol concentration level of less than:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "273", "correct": "false", "text": "0.00%"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "273", "correct": "false", "text": "0.03%"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "273", "correct": "true", "text": "0.05%"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "273", "correct": "false", "text": "0.08%"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_9", "question": "When may you not lend your driver's licence?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "274", "correct": "false", "text": "In emergencies"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "274", "correct": "false", "text": "To a person learning to drive"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "274", "correct": "true", "text": "It is not permitted"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "274", "correct": "false", "text": "For identification purpose"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_10", "question": "If you are a teenage driver, after six months of obtaining your G2 licence and until you obtain your G licence or turn 20, how many teenage passengers are you allowed to carry between midnight to 5 a.m.?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "282", "correct": "false", "text": "1 passenger aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "282", "correct": "false", "text": "2 passengers aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "282", "correct": "true", "text": "3 passengers aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "282", "correct": "false", "text": "No passengers aged 19 or under"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_11", "question": "As a class G2 driver, your blood alcohol concentration level must not be over:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "299", "correct": "false", "text": "0.08%"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "299", "correct": "false", "text": "0.05%"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "299", "correct": "false", "text": "0.03%"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "299", "correct": "true", "text": "0.00%"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_12", "question": "As a Level One (Class G1) or Level Two (Class G2) driver, your licence will be suspended if you collect:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "327", "correct": "false", "text": "Two or more demerit points"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "327", "correct": "false", "text": "Six demerit points"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "327", "correct": "true", "text": "Nine or more demerit points during a two-year period"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "327", "correct": "false", "text": "10 or more demerit points"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_13", "question": "As a Level One (Class G1) or Level Two (Class G2) driver, the first time you collect the maximum number of demerit points, your licence will be suspended for", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "328", "correct": "false", "text": "30 days"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "328", "correct": "true", "text": "60 days"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "328", "correct": "false", "text": "90 days"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "328", "correct": "false", "text": "120 days"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_14", "question": "If you are a teenage driver aged 19 or under in the first six months after obtaining your G2 licence, how many teenage passengers are you allowed to carry between midnight to 5 a.m.?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "234", "correct": "true", "text": "1 passenger aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "234", "correct": "false", "text": "2 passengers aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "234", "correct": "false", "text": "3 passengers aged 19 or under"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "234", "correct": "false", "text": "No passengers aged 19 or under"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_15", "question": "Which of the following has the right-of-way when the light is green?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "235", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicles turning right with the green light"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "235", "correct": "true", "text": "Pedestrians crossing with the green light"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "235", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicles turning left with the green light"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "235", "correct": "false", "text": "Pedestrians crossing against the light"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_16", "question": "When driving on a one-way street, which lane must you be in to make a left turn?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "236", "correct": "false", "text": "Closest to the right side of the road"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "236", "correct": "true", "text": "Closest to the left side of the road"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "236", "correct": "false", "text": "You may make a left turn on any lane"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "236", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above are correct"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_17", "question": "When making a right turn at a red light, what must you check before making the turn?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "237", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop, signal and check for pedestrians"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "237", "correct": "false", "text": "Check if there are any restrictions against making a right turn"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "237", "correct": "false", "text": "Check for vehicles going straight with the green light"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "237", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_18", "question": "What should you do if you approach an intersection and the light changes from green to yellow?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "238", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop, if stopping is unsafe to do so then proceed with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "238", "correct": "false", "text": "Accelerate your vehicle through intersection before the yellow light turns red"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "238", "correct": "false", "text": "Change nothing and drive through"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "238", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_19", "question": "Is there a seat belt law in Ontario?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "240", "correct": "true", "text": "Yes"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "240", "correct": "false", "text": "No"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "240", "correct": "false", "text": "Yes, you must wear a seat belt if you are under the age of 16"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "240", "correct": "false", "text": "Yes, You must wear a seat belt if you are over the age of 16"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_20", "question": "You are approaching a school bus with flashing red lights, what should you do?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "242", "correct": "false", "text": "Proceed ahead with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "242", "correct": "true", "text": "Come to a complete stop and only proceed when the flashing red lights are off"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "242", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass with care to the left of the school bus"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "242", "correct": "false", "text": "Wait for vehicles to pass on the opposing side and then pass the school bus on the opposing lane"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_21", "question": "Is the driver responsible for their passengers buckling up?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "244", "correct": "false", "text": "Only if passengers are over sixteen years of age"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "244", "correct": "true", "text": "Only if passengers are under the age of sixteen"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "244", "correct": "false", "text": "Only if the passengers are in the front seat"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "244", "correct": "false", "text": "Only if passengers are under eighteen years of age"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_22", "question": "When headlights are required, the drivers must use low beams when following another vehicle:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "245", "correct": "false", "text": "When less than 30 m (100 ft.) from the vehicle in front"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "245", "correct": "true", "text": "When less than 60 m (200 ft.) from the vehicle in front"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "245", "correct": "false", "text": "When less than 120 m (400 ft.) from the vehicle infront"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "245", "correct": "false", "text": "This does not apply to divided roads"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_23", "question": "Except when overtaking or passing another vehicle, what distance must be maintained between commercial vehicles and other vehicles on the highway?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "246", "correct": "false", "text": "30 m (100 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "246", "correct": "true", "text": "60 m (200 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "246", "correct": "false", "text": "120 m (400 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "246", "correct": "false", "text": "150 m (500 ft.)"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_24", "question": "Unless otherwise posted, the maximum speed limit outside of cities, towns and villages is:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "248", "correct": "false", "text": "70 km/h"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "248", "correct": "true", "text": "80 km/h"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "248", "correct": "false", "text": "90 km/h"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "248", "correct": "false", "text": "100 km/h"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_25", "question": "When approaching a stop sign, a driver must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "249", "correct": "false", "text": "Come to a complete stop, check for pedestrians and then proceed"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "249", "correct": "false", "text": "Drive slowly while passing the sign"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "249", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down, let the right of way pass and then proceed"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "249", "correct": "true", "text": "Come to a complete stop, check for vehicles and pedestrians and then proceed when it is safe"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_26", "question": "What does a red signalling light mean with a green arrow at an intersection?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "250", "correct": "true", "text": "Vehicles may proceed with caution in the direction of the arrow"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "250", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicles must stop if proceeding straight"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "250", "correct": "false", "text": "Pedestrians have the right-of-way"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "250", "correct": "false", "text": "You must wait for the green arrow to disappear before making a turn in the direction of the arrow"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_27", "question": "When you approach an intersection with a flashing yellow traffic light, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "251", "correct": "true", "text": "Slow down and proceed with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "251", "correct": "false", "text": "Come to a complete stop then proceed with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "251", "correct": "false", "text": "Not slow down and proceed right away"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "251", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above are correct"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_28", "question": "You must report any accident to the police when there are injuries or when the damage exceeds:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "252", "correct": "false", "text": "$500"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "252", "correct": "false", "text": "$1,000"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "252", "correct": "false", "text": "$1,500"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "252", "correct": "true", "text": "$2,000"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_29", "question": "You are required to keep a safe distance behind the vehicle in front of you at 50 km/h (30 m.p.h.), you should keep at least:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "253", "correct": "false", "text": "Seven car lengths behind the other vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "253", "correct": "true", "text": "Three car lengths behind the other vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "253", "correct": "false", "text": "One car lengths behind the other vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "253", "correct": "false", "text": "Five car lengths behind the other vehicle"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_30", "question": "What does a flashing blue light on a vehicle mean?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "254", "correct": "false", "text": "Construction vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "254", "correct": "true", "text": "Snow removal vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "254", "correct": "false", "text": "Emergency vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "254", "correct": "false", "text": "Tow truck"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_31", "question": "If you are involved in an accident where an injury occurs, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "256", "correct": "false", "text": "Report the accident to your immediate family only"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "256", "correct": "false", "text": "Report the accident within 24 hours to the police"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "256", "correct": "true", "text": "Report the accident at once to the police"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "256", "correct": "false", "text": "Report the accident to your insurance company only"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_32", "question": "When trying to enter the traffic flow from a parked position on the curb, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "257", "correct": "false", "text": "Check for oncoming traffic, signal and pull from curb quickly"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "257", "correct": "false", "text": "Signal and pull from the curb after checking your mirrors"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "257", "correct": "true", "text": "Check for oncoming traffic, signal and pull from the curb when it is safe to do so"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "257", "correct": "false", "text": "Signal and pull from the curb after checking for pedestrians"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_33", "question": "What penalties can a driver face when convicted of driving while their licence is suspended:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "259", "correct": "false", "text": "A fine of $1,000-$5,000 or imprisonment for 6 months or both for a first offence"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "259", "correct": "false", "text": "A fine of $2,000-$5,000 or imprisonment for 6 months or both for a subsequent offence within 5 years"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "259", "correct": "false", "text": "Up to 6 months may be added to your current suspension time"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "259", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_34", "question": "When approaching an intersection, you notice a traffic jam ahead, what should you do?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "260", "correct": "false", "text": "Proceed ahead and keep close to the vehicle in front of you"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "260", "correct": "false", "text": "Proceed slowly into the intersection"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "260", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop behind the line and only proceed when the traffic ahead moves forward"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "260", "correct": "false", "text": "Maintain your speed and stop regularly behind traffic"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_35", "question": "When approaching an intersection where the traffic light is red and a policeman signals you to go through. What should you do?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "263", "correct": "true", "text": "Obey the policeman's signal and proceed"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "263", "correct": "false", "text": "Let the police officer know that the traffic light is red"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "263", "correct": "false", "text": "Wait for the light to turn green"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "263", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop and speak to the officer to make sure they are signalling to you"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_36", "question": "When a streetcar stops and opens the doors, what does the law require you to do before passing the streetcar?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "264", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop behind the rear of the streetcar and then proceed"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "264", "correct": "false", "text": "Sound your horn and pass with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "264", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass on the left side if the way is clear"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "264", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop behind the rearmost door; only proceed when the doors are closed and when it is safe"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_37", "question": "What does the law require you to do when you hear the sirens of an emergency vehicle on a regular two-way street?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "268", "correct": "false", "text": "Speed up so you can out run the emergency vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "268", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down and let the emergency vehicle pass"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "268", "correct": "true", "text": "Pull over to the right as far as you can and come to a complete stop"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "268", "correct": "false", "text": "Continue at same speed while"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_38", "question": "If you fail to stop for a school bus that has flashing red lights on, what are the consequences for the first offence?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "270", "correct": "true", "text": "A fine of $400-$2,000 and 6 demerit points"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "270", "correct": "false", "text": "A fine of up to $1,000 and 6 demerit points"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "270", "correct": "false", "text": "Only 6 demerit points"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "270", "correct": "false", "text": "Only a fine of up to $2,000"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_39", "question": "The Zero BAC law states that certain drivers may not have any blood alcohol concentration while they drive. Who does this law apply to?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "271", "correct": "true", "text": "Novice drivers of any age and drivers age 21 and under"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "271", "correct": "false", "text": "Pregnant women"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "271", "correct": "false", "text": "Only drivers age 21 and under"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "271", "correct": "false", "text": "Only novice drivers"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_40", "question": "Unless otherwise posted,the maximum speed limit in a city,town,village or built-up area is:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "272", "correct": "false", "text": "30 km/h (20 m.p.h.)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "272", "correct": "false", "text": "40 km/h (25 m.p.h.)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "272", "correct": "true", "text": "50 km/h (30 m.p.h.)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "272", "correct": "false", "text": "60 km/h (35 m.p.h.)"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_41", "question": "When a truck becomes disabled on the highway, flares or reflectors must be placed approximately what distance ahead of and to the rear of the disabled vehicle?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "275", "correct": "false", "text": "15 m (50 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "275", "correct": "true", "text": "30 m (100 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "275", "correct": "false", "text": "60 m (200 ft.)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "275", "correct": "false", "text": "90 m (300 ft.)"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_42", "question": "What documents may a police officer require a motor vehicle owner to produce?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "278", "correct": "false", "text": "Valid insurance"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "278", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicle ownership"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "278", "correct": "false", "text": "Valid driver's license"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "278", "correct": "true", "text": "Any or all of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_43", "question": "When a streetcar stops and opens its doors at a safety island, what does the law require you to do?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "291", "correct": "false", "text": "Come to a stop and wait until the doors close before you proceed"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "291", "correct": "false", "text": "Wait until there are no pedestrians before proceeding"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "291", "correct": "true", "text": "Proceed with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "291", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop 2 m behind the stop signs on the streetcar doors"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_44", "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "292", "correct": "false", "text": "You must not park within 3 m of a fire hydrant"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "292", "correct": "false", "text": "You must not park within 100 m of a bridge"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "292", "correct": "true", "text": "You must not park on a hill if you do not have a clear view of at least 50 m in both direction"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "292", "correct": "false", "text": "You must not park within 15 m from a railway crossing"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_45", "question": "When traveling on  a highway, the driver of a motor vehicle is not permitted to carry in a house or boat trailer:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "296", "correct": "false", "text": "Firearms"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "296", "correct": "false", "text": "Flammable materials"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "296", "correct": "true", "text": "Person(s)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "296", "correct": "false", "text": "Pets"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_46", "question": "Cellular phone can be an important safety aid for drivers,However,using a cellular phone while driving:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "297", "correct": "false", "text": "Is safe only if a hands-free system is used"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "297", "correct": "false", "text": "Is acceptable for drivers with four or more years of driving exoerience"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "297", "correct": "false", "text": "Is safe only when weather conditions are good"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "297", "correct": "true", "text": "Interferes with your ability to drive safely"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_47", "question": "As a class G1 driver, you must be accompanied by a class G driver. How many years of experience must the class G driver have?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "298", "correct": "false", "text": "One year"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "298", "correct": "false", "text": "Two years"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "298", "correct": "false", "text": "Three years"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "298", "correct": "true", "text": "Four years"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_48", "question": "Never change lanes in the traffic without:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "308", "correct": "false", "text": "Looking in the rear view mirror only"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "308", "correct": "true", "text": "Giving proper signal and looking to make sure the move can be made safely"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "308", "correct": "false", "text": "Blowing your horn and looking to the rear"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "308", "correct": "false", "text": "Decreasing speed and giving correct signal"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_49", "question": "When the driver of another vehicle is about to overtake and pass your vehicle, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "309", "correct": "false", "text": "Speed up so that passing is not necessary"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "309", "correct": "false", "text": "Move to the left to prevent passing"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "309", "correct": "false", "text": "Signal the other driver not to pass"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "309", "correct": "true", "text": "Move to the right and allow such vehicle to pass"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_50", "question": "Which of the following has the right-of-way over all others at an intersection where the signal light is green?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "310", "correct": "true", "text": "Pedestrians crossing with the light"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "310", "correct": "false", "text": "Pedestrians crossing against the light"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "310", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicle turning right"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "310", "correct": "false", "text": "Vehicle turning left"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_51", "question": "Which of the following hand-and-arm signals is correct for slowing or stopping?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "311", "correct": "true", "text": "Arm out and down"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "311", "correct": "false", "text": "Circle motion"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "311", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm out and up"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "311", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm straight out the window"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_52", "question": "What must a driver do before entering a highway from a private road or driveway?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "312", "correct": "false", "text": "Enter or cross the highway as quickly as possible"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "312", "correct": "true", "text": "Yield right-of-way to all vehicles approaching on the highway"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "312", "correct": "false", "text": "Sound horn and proceed with caution"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "312", "correct": "false", "text": "Give hand signal, then take right-of-way"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_53", "question": "Which of the following hand-and-arm signals is correct for a right turn?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "313", "correct": "true", "text": "Arm out and up"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "313", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm out and down"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "313", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm straight out the window"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "313", "correct": "false", "text": "Circle motion"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_54", "question": "Upon approaching an intersection marked with a “Yield” sign, you are required to:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "314", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop, then enter intersection slowly"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "314", "correct": "true", "text": "Enter intersection only when way is clear"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "314", "correct": "false", "text": "Keep same speed and look left and right"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "314", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop, then enter the intersection quickly"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_55", "question": "Parking lights may be used:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "315", "correct": "false", "text": "When driving on well lighted streets"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "315", "correct": "false", "text": "When driving in heavy fog"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "315", "correct": "false", "text": "At any time"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "315", "correct": "true", "text": "For parking only"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_56", "question": "When does the law require lights on your vehicle to be turned on?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "316", "correct": "true", "text": "Between 1/2 hour before sunset to 1/2 hour after sunrise and at any other time you cannot see clearly for a distance of 150 metres (500 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "316", "correct": "false", "text": "Between dusk and dawn and at any other time you cannot see clearly for a distance of 150 metres (500 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "316", "correct": "false", "text": "Between sunset and sunrise"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "316", "correct": "false", "text": "No specific time"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_57", "question": "A flashing red light at an intersection means:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "317", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop, proceed only when it is safe to do so"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "317", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down and yield right-of-way to cars approaching from your left or right"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "317", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop, proceed only when the light changes to green"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "317", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down and drive with increased caution"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_58", "question": "A flashing blue light on a motor vehicle indicates:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "318", "correct": "true", "text": "Snow removal equipment"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "318", "correct": "false", "text": "A motor vehicle carrying explosives"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "318", "correct": "false", "text": "A public utility emergency vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "318", "correct": "false", "text": "An ambulance"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_59", "question": "Before leaving your car parked on a downgrade, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "319", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn your front wheels to the left and set your parking brake"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "319", "correct": "false", "text": "Set your parking brake only"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "319", "correct": "false", "text": "Leave your front wheels parallel to the curb"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "319", "correct": "true", "text": "Turn your front wheels to the right and set your parking brake"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_60", "question": "When you are deciding whether or not to make a U-turn, your first consideration should be to check:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "320", "correct": "true", "text": "Traffic regulations"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "320", "correct": "false", "text": "Presence of trees, fire hydrants or poles near the curb"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "320", "correct": "false", "text": "Turning radius of your car"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "320", "correct": "false", "text": "Height of curb"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_61", "question": "When a flashing green light is shown at an intersection:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "321", "correct": "false", "text": "You must not attempt to make a left turn"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "321", "correct": "false", "text": "You must stop and proceed when the light stops flashing"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "321", "correct": "true", "text": "You must proceed straight through or turn to the left or right"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "321", "correct": "false", "text": "The flashing green light is for pedestrians only"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_62", "question": "To get your vehicle out of a skid, you should first:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "322", "correct": "false", "text": "Steer straight ahead"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "322", "correct": "false", "text": "Steer in the opposite direction of the skid"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "322", "correct": "true", "text": "Look where you want to go and steer in that direction"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "322", "correct": "false", "text": "Apply brakes hard"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_63", "question": "A solid centre line on the roadway is on your side of a broken centre line. What does the solid centre line mean?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "323", "correct": "true", "text": "It is unsafe to overtake and pass"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "323", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass at any time"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "323", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass only when no traffic is in sight"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "323", "correct": "false", "text": "It is safe to overtake and pass"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_64", "question": "When a car is stopped to allow a pedestrian to cross the street at a marked crosswalk, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "324", "correct": "true", "text": "Not pass any car stopped to allow a pedestrian to cross"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "324", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass the stopped car of the right"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "324", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass the stopped car of the left"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "324", "correct": "false", "text": "Sound horn for the driver of the stopped car to drive on"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_65", "question": "How close to a fire hydrant may you legally park?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "325", "correct": "false", "text": "1.5 metres (5 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "325", "correct": "true", "text": "3 metres (10 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "325", "correct": "false", "text": "4.5 metres (15 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "325", "correct": "false", "text": "6 metres (20 feet)"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_66", "question": "In what lane of traffic should you drive when you are going to make a right turn?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "326", "correct": "false", "text": "Close to the centre line of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "326", "correct": "true", "text": "Close to the right side of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "326", "correct": "false", "text": "Close to the left side of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "326", "correct": "false", "text": "Does not matter if you give proper signal"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_67", "question": " Some driving offences, including convictions for careless driving and driving 50 km/h or more over the speed limit, can result in:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "329", "correct": "false", "text": "Demerit points only"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "329", "correct": "false", "text": "Fines only"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "329", "correct": "true", "text": "Demerit points, fines and suspension of your driver’s licence"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "329", "correct": "false", "text": "Suspension of your driver’s licence"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_68", "question": "You may driver while your licence suspended only if:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "330", "correct": "false", "text": "You have not surrendered your licence to the Ministry of Transportation"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "330", "correct": "false", "text": "You consider yourself to be a highly skilled driver"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "330", "correct": "false", "text": "You drive only during the daytime"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "330", "correct": "true", "text": "You may not, under any circumstances, drive while your licence is suspended"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_69", "question": "If your refuse to give a breath or blood sample to the police when asked, or if you register over the legal limit on a breath or blood test, your licence will be suspended immediately at the roadside or police station for:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "332", "correct": "true", "text": "90 days"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "332", "correct": "false", "text": "120 days"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "332", "correct": "false", "text": "150 days"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "332", "correct": "false", "text": "180 days"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_70", "question": " The first time you are convicted of a Criminal Code offence, your licence will be suspended for at least:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "333", "correct": "true", "text": "One year"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "333", "correct": "false", "text": "Two years"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "333", "correct": "false", "text": "Three years"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "333", "correct": "false", "text": "Four years"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_71", "question": "When driving, the most dangerous position on the road is:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "334", "correct": "false", "text": "Two seconds or more behind another vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "334", "correct": "false", "text": "Two car lengths behind another vehicle two lanes over"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "334", "correct": "true", "text": "In the blind spot of another vehicle"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "334", "correct": "false", "text": "Two car lengths in front of another vehicle"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_72", "question": "If you cause a collision while using a cellular phone:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "335", "correct": "false", "text": "Your insurance premium may increase"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "335", "correct": "true", "text": "You can be charged with careless driving, and if convicted, you will receive six demerit points and can be fined up to $1,000 and sentenced to six months in jail"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "335", "correct": "false", "text": "You may be charged with careless driving, but not be convicted"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "335", "correct": "false", "text": "You will not be charged"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_73", "question": "In what position on the roadway must you be before making a left turn from a one-way street? (Repeat)", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "336", "correct": "false", "text": "Close to the right side of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "336", "correct": "true", "text": "Close to the left side of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "336", "correct": "false", "text": "Close to the centre line of the roadway"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "336", "correct": "false", "text": "Does not matter if you give proper signal"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_74", "question": " Never make a U-turn unless you can see at least _______ in both directions.", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "370", "correct": "false", "text": "50m"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "370", "correct": "false", "text": "125m"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "370", "correct": "false", "text": "250m"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "370", "correct": "true", "text": "150m"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_75", "question": "Coming to a complete stop at an intersection is required, but where do you stop if there is no stop line, crosswalk or sidewalk?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "371", "correct": "false", "text": "Right before the stop sign"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "371", "correct": "false", "text": "A little into the intersection"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "371", "correct": "false", "text": "Right beside the stop sign"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "371", "correct": "true", "text": "At the edge of the intersection"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_76", "question": "What should you do if you feel drowsy while driving?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "372", "correct": "false", "text": "Open a window"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "372", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn up your radio"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "372", "correct": "false", "text": "Reduce speed"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "372", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop for a short rest in a safe area"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_77", "question": "If you want to pass a motorcycle,you should", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "381", "correct": "true", "text": "pass just as would with another car."}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "381", "correct": "false", "text": "use half of their lane to pass."}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "381", "correct": "false", "text": "honk your horn before you pass."}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "381", "correct": "false", "text": "turn on your high-beam lights before you pass."}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_78", "question": "When driving in heavy fog,you should use", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "382", "correct": "false", "text": "parking lights."}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "382", "correct": "true", "text": "low-beam headlights"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "382", "correct": "false", "text": "parking lights and high-beam headlights."}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "382", "correct": "false", "text": "high-beam headlights."}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_79", "question": "You may NOT park within------of an intersection that is NOT controlled by traffic lights.", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "383", "correct": "false", "text": "5 metres."}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "383", "correct": "false", "text": "7 metres."}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "383", "correct": "true", "text": "9 metres."}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "383", "correct": "false", "text": "15 metres."}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_80", "question": "Under Ontario's Move Over low,you are required to", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "384", "correct": "false", "text": "move into the rightmost lane if you are driving slower than other traffic."}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "384", "correct": "true", "text": "change lanes if safe when passing a stopped emergency vehicle with its lights flashing."}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "384", "correct": "false", "text": "pull over if an emergency vehicle is following you with its lights flashing."}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "384", "correct": "false", "text": "do none of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_81", "question": "If you are passing a cyclist, how much room should you leave between your vehicle and the cyclist", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "385", "correct": "true", "text": "1 metre"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "385", "correct": "false", "text": "2 metres"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "385", "correct": "false", "text": "3 metres"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "385", "correct": "false", "text": "4 metres"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_82", "question": "Why is it necessary to check over your shoulder when changing lanes?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "232", "correct": "false", "text": "So you do not have to check your mirrors"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "232", "correct": "false", "text": "It makes it easier to change lanes when you are facing the direction"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "232", "correct": "true", "text": "To check your blind spots"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "232", "correct": "false", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_83", "question": "When two vehicles meet at an intersection that has all-ways stop signs, who has the right-of-way:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "233", "correct": "true", "text": "The vehicle on your right side"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "233", "correct": "false", "text": "The vehicle on your left side"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "233", "correct": "false", "text": "Both of you have the right of way"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "233", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_84", "question": "You should always drive at a speed which will allow you to:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "241", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop within 60 meters (200 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "241", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop within 90 meters (300 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "241", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop within 150 meters (500 feet)"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "241", "correct": "true", "text": "Stop within a safe distance"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_85", "question": "If you want to pass a motorcycle, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "243", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn on your high beam lights, as the driver on the motorcycle has small mirrors"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "243", "correct": "false", "text": "Flash your high beam lights to get the driver's attention"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "243", "correct": "true", "text": "Treat the motorcycle as any other vehicle and pass it normally"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "243", "correct": "false", "text": "Use half of the lane to pass the motorcycle"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_86", "question": "When should you yield to the right of way ?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "255", "correct": "false", "text": "At an intersection without signs or lights, yield to the first vehicle or if both vehicles stop at the same time, yield to the vehicle approaching from the right"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "255", "correct": "false", "text": "When entering the road from a private road or driveway, yield to the pedestrians and traffic on the road "}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "255", "correct": "false", "text": "At a pedestrian crossings and school crossings with crossing guards."}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "255", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_87", "question": "Most automobile skids are the result of:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "258", "correct": "true", "text": "Driving too fast"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "258", "correct": "false", "text": "Hard breaking on the road"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "258", "correct": "false", "text": "Aggressive turning on the road"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "258", "correct": "false", "text": "Making U-Turns"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_88", "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "266", "correct": "false", "text": "When 6 demerit points have been accumulated, a letter will be sent to you advising you to improve your driving skills"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "266", "correct": "false", "text": "When 9 demerit points have been accumulated, you may be called in for an interview and a driver re-examination"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "266", "correct": "false", "text": "When 15 demerit points have been accumulated, your licence will be suspended for 30 days"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "266", "correct": "true", "text": "When 15 demerit points have been accumulated, you will lose your licence for up to 2 years"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_89", "question": "What must you do when switching lanes in traffic?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "276", "correct": "false", "text": "Signal correctly and check your mirrors before switching lanes"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "276", "correct": "false", "text": "Check your blind spots before switching lanes"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "276", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn off your signal after switching lanes"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "276", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_90", "question": "Which of the following hand-and-arm signals is correct for slowing or stopping?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "277", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm out and up"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "277", "correct": "false", "text": "Arm straight out the window"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "277", "correct": "true", "text": "Arm out and down"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "277", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_91", "question": "When another vehicle wants to overtake and pass your vehicle, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "279", "correct": "false", "text": "Reduce your speed to keep the vehicle behind you"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "279", "correct": "false", "text": "Accelerate to keep the traffic flowing"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "279", "correct": "true", "text": "Move to the right and allow the vehicle to pass"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "279", "correct": "false", "text": "Move to the left to prevent the vehicle from passing"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_92", "question": "What is the best way to stop quickly on a wet or icy road?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "280", "correct": "false", "text": "Take your foot off the gas pedal and focus on your steering as your car slows down"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "280", "correct": "true", "text": "Pump the brake until you come to a stop"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "280", "correct": "false", "text": "Step on the brakes as you normally would"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "280", "correct": "false", "text": "Fully step on the brakes to prevent skidding"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_93", "question": "When driving in heavy fog,you should use:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "281", "correct": "false", "text": "High beam head lights to increase your range of vision"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "281", "correct": "true", "text": "Low beam headlights to increase your nearby vision"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "281", "correct": "false", "text": "Parking lights"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "281", "correct": "false", "text": "Parking lights and high beam headlights"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_94", "question": "When parking downhill on the road curb, you must:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "283", "correct": "false", "text": "Use your parking breaks to prevent the car from rolling down the hill"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "283", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn your front wheels to the left and set your parking brake"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "283", "correct": "true", "text": "Turn your front wheels to the right and set your parking brake"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "283", "correct": "false", "text": "Park like you normally would"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_95", "question": "If you are driving on a road and suddenly your right tire goes off the road, what is the safest way to get back on the road?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "284", "correct": "false", "text": "Apply the gas pedal and steer hard to the left"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "284", "correct": "false", "text": "Apply the brakes and steer hard to the left"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "284", "correct": "true", "text": "Take your foot off the gas pedal, and steer left when vehicle has slowed down"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "284", "correct": "false", "text": "Apply the brakes and steer hard to the right"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_96", "question": "When is a u-turn prohibited?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "285", "correct": "false", "text": "When there's a \"No U-Turn Sign\""}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "285", "correct": "false", "text": "On a railroad crossing or within 30 m (100 ft.) of a railroad crossing"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "285", "correct": "false", "text": "On a hill where the driver's view is less than 150 m (500 ft.) in both directions"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "285", "correct": "true", "text": "All of above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_97", "question": "When entering a freeway you should signal,then:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "286", "correct": "false", "text": "Stop on acceleration lane,wait for an opening,then enter the freeway rapidly"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "286", "correct": "false", "text": "Drive slowly and be prepared to stop for freeway traffic"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "286", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down,enter the freeway at a sharp angle"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "286", "correct": "true", "text": "Accelerate quickly to freeway speed and merge with freeway traffic"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_98", "question": "A broken center line on a roadway means you may:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "287", "correct": "false", "text": "Never pass"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "287", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass at any time"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "287", "correct": "true", "text": "Pass if the way is clear"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "287", "correct": "false", "text": "Pass only during daylight hours"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_99", "question": "When you are driving along the road, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "288", "correct": "false", "text": "Always keep to the middle lane"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "288", "correct": "true", "text": "Always keep to the right"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "288", "correct": "false", "text": "Always keep to the left"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "288", "correct": "false", "text": "None of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_100", "question": "If you are planning to making a U-Turn, what is the first thing you should check before making a U-Turn?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "289", "correct": "false", "text": "The amount of space needed for a U-Turn"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "289", "correct": "false", "text": "The pedestrians"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "289", "correct": "true", "text": "A No U-Turn Sign"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "289", "correct": "false", "text": "The oncoming vehicles"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_101", "question": "If you are driving and suddenly one of your tires blows out, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "290", "correct": "false", "text": "Concentrate on steering wheel"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "290", "correct": "false", "text": "Take your foot off the gas pedal to reduce the vehicle speed"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "290", "correct": "false", "text": "Try and bring the vehicle to a stop off the road"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "290", "correct": "true", "text": "All of the above"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_102", "question": " At night, when you meet another vehicle with blinding bright lights, what is the safest thing to do?", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "294", "correct": "false", "text": "Open and shut your eyes rapidly"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "294", "correct": "false", "text": "Turn on your high beam lights"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "294", "correct": "false", "text": "Look where you want to go and steer in that direction"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "294", "correct": "true", "text": "Look slightly to the right"}]}, {"type": "rule", "id": "rule_103", "question": "When approaching an intersection and the traffic lights are not working, you should:", "options": [{"option_id": "option_1", "question_id": "295", "correct": "false", "text": "Yield to the traffic to your right"}, {"option_id": "option_2", "question_id": "295", "correct": "false", "text": "Wait until there are no vehicles before proceeding"}, {"option_id": "option_3", "question_id": "295", "correct": "true", "text": "Treat it as an all-ways stop sign"}, {"option_id": "option_4", "question_id": "295", "correct": "false", "text": "Slow down and proceed with caution"}]}]}